Victor A. Lora

15 Grove Street ♦ Ridgefield Park, NJ 07660 ♦ (201) 289-1355 ♦ victor@victorlora.net ♦ LinkedIn: vlora95

COMPUTER SCIENCE

An upcoming graduate offering a strong academic background in Computer Science, Mathematics and Physics combined with excellent internship experience as a Software Developer and NOC Engineer. Consistently recognized for technical troubleshooting skills used to rapidly and cost-effectively resolve challenging technical issues. Solid experience learning and mastering new technologies. Strong skills in a range of computer systems, languages, tools and testing methodologies. Equally successful in both team and self-directed settings. Demonstrated ability to handle highly sensitive and confidential information. Multi-lingual speaking English, Italian and Spanish. Academic career distinguished by attaining Dean's List every semester and a 3.8/4.0 GPA.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, Muhlenberg College, Allentown, PA 2017

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Object Oriented Languages
- Front End/Back End Coding
- Web Development
- Database Administration
- Portal Development

- Computer Vision
- Software/Hardware
- Leadership
- Communication
- Technical Support

- Problem Resolution
- Customer Relationships
- Office Management
- SLA Achievement
- Shipping/Inventory

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Front-End Coding: CSS; HTML5; JavaScript
- Back-End Coding: C; C++; Java; PHP; Python; SQL; Swift 2.0
- Tools & Frameworks: Git; GitHub; Linux; MySQL; OSX; Postgres; Redmine; SmartGWT; Spring

ENGINEERING/SUPPORT EXPERIENCE

- Developed an obstruction detection algorithm that prevents camera tampering on customer buses.
- Construct and maintain web services and applications used in customer portals.
- Resolved functional and technical issues by troubleshooting and diagnosing hardware and software issues onsite, over the phone, and by email.
- Documented help desk tickets/resolutions as well as system configurations and technical procedures.
- Collaborated with a four-person team in the development of an iOS application that promotes energy efficient vehicles.

WORK HISTORY

SAUCON TECHNOLOGIES, Bethlehem, PA, Software Developer Intern NU-AGE MANAGED SERVICES, Pearl River, NY, NOC Engineer Intern KUTZTOWN UNIVERSITY (Cantalobber Competition), Kutztown, PA, Engineer/Competitor DEAN OF STUDENTS OFFICE MUHLENBERG COLLEGE, Allentown, PA, Work Study Assistant 2015-Present 2014-2015 2014 & 2015 2013-2015

AWARDS & HONORS

Presidential Merit Scholarship, 2013 - Present
Emerging Leaders Program Member/Mentor, inducted 2013
Cardinal Key Society Member, inducted 2013
Judicial Panel Member, inducted 2014
Peer Tutor, 2015 - Present